Micah Levi Rabinowitz 2462 S Edmunds St, Seattle, WA 98108

Cell: (901) 651-2222 **Email:** micahrabinowitz@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/micah-rabinowitz

GitHub: https://github.com/Turbocake64

Skype: micah.rabinowitz

Roles/Responsibilities:

- Web Developer
- Project management
- Event coordination
- · Cultural exchange
- Community organization

Languages

- English native
- Japanese JLPT highest level

Additional Training:

- · TOEFL teaching certification
- Japanese Government Teaching Certification for beginning students.
- Japanese-English Translation Interpretation Certification from JIAM
- MERN Stack Web
 Development Certification

Programming Languages:

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Node
- Express
- MYSQL
- MONGO
- React

Projects:

Recipeasy

Recipe search and cooking diary app. Uses HTML, CSS, JS, and Firebase. Github

• UO

An app to be paired with Venmo/Papal, UO logs money borrowed between people. Uses Node, Express, MYSQL, JS, CSS, HTML. Github **Experience Summary:** Recent full stack web development boot camp graduate and eager learner with years of experience abroad.

Key Strengths:

- MERN stack developer eager to enter the work force.
- Experienced at learning on the job.
- Flexible and reliable able to work across many teams/projects at the same time efficiently.
- · Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite.

Work History:

Coordinator of International Relations (CIR) through Japanese Exchange and Teaching (JET) Kitagawa Village, Kochi 2016-2018:

Contracted through the Kitagawa BoE, this position is responsible for coordinating cultural events for children, writing a monthly Japanese column, translating and interpreting for local businesses, English education, and engaging the public as a cultural liaison.

English Language Teacher for the AtoZ Corporation Azumino City, Nagano 2014-2016:

Hired through AtoZ to work in the Azumino City school system, this position required developing an English curriculum and implementing it in 3 elementary schools around the city.

University of Memphis Intensive English for Internationals ESL Instructor Memphis, Tennessee June 2013- March 2014

Taught foundational listening, speaking, reading, and pronunciation to multicultural classes. Interpreted orientation for Japanese exchange students.

Volunteer History:

Stonewall Japan Shikoku Block Leader 2017-2018:

Planned and organized turnkey events for region wide community building. Wrote a monthly newsletter which saw around 50% increased readership. Went to each prefecture to build community connection and appoint regional leaders to welcome new members into the organization and plan local events.

Tosaben Genki Musical Project Manager Spring 2018:

Developed the timeline and oversaw the actions list for the charity musical. Handled all correspondence from production team to cast and crew. Despite a 40% downsizing from 2017, 2018 brought in similar crowds, raised comparable donations, and honored 8 times the scholarships as the previous year.

University of Memphis IEI Student Community Outreach 2013-2014:

Volunteered to bring students to community events and help students to overcome language/cultural barriers to connect to University of Memphis student body and surrounding communities.

Education:

University of Washington: Full –time MERN Stack Web Development certification

J. F. Oberlin University: 1 year study abroad: Japanese Intensive

University of Memphis, Double Major: Bachelor of Arts in Applied Linguistics & Japanese